A Guide to the Bland County (Va.) Records, 1861-1957
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Bland County (Va.) Records, 1861-1957
Library of Virginia
1015383-1015386, 1015388, 1015390, 1015406, 1097588, 1097638, 1151851-1151853
12 boxes and/or volumes
Bland County (Va.) Circuit Court
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a shipment of court papers from Bland County.
Historical Information
Bland County is said to have been named for Richard Bland, a leader of colonial Virginia's resistance to Great Britain in the 1760s and 1770s. It was formed from Giles, Wythe, and Tazewell Counties in 1861, and another part of Giles was added in 1900. Its area is 369 square miles, and the county seat is Bland.
Scope and Content
Bland County (Va.) Records, 1861-1957, includes miscellaneous records from the following series: Circuit Court Records, County Court Records, Justice of the Peace Records, Election Records, Marriage Records and Vital Statistics, Fiduciary Records, Land Records, Military and Pension Records, Tax and Fiscal Records, Clerk's Records, Board of Supervisors, and Road and Bridge Records.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Bland County Court Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm."
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Bland County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records -- Virginia -- Bland County.
Geographical Names:
Bland County (Va.) -- History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records -- Virginia -- Bland County.
Contents List
- Records, 1896-1901
  Commonwealth Causes, Road and Bridge Records, and Jury Records.
- Records, 1889-1895
- Records, 1881-1903
  Judgments Confessed, Abstracts of Votes, and Constable's Returns
- Records, 1902-1903
  Judgments, Commonwealth Causes, Sleeping Papers, Disposed and Current Papers, Old Law Papers, Road and Bridge Records.
- Records, 1888-1921
  Constable's Returns and Dockets and Liquour License Reports.
- Records, 1862-1946
  Personal Papers of G. R. Repass [court clerk], 1895-1946; Health and Medical Records: Lunacy Papers, 1912-1936; Tax and Fiscal Records: Orders for Claims, 1902-1913; Marriage and Vital Statistics: Orders for Marriage Licenses, 1913-1925.
- Records, 1867-1927
  Birth and Death Lists, Certificates of Births and Deaths, Fiduciary Settlements, and Sale and Appraisement Bills Recorded.
- Records, 1867-1903
  Common Law Rule Docket (includes County and Circuit Court).
- Records, 1861-1896
  County Court Records: Pleas, 1861-1862; Military and Pension Records: Board of Exemption Minutes, 1862-1863; Board of Supervisors: Minute Book, 1870-1896.
- Records, 1889-1911
  Deeds and lists of heirs.
- Records, 1912-1929
- Records, 1930-1957, 1960